Will the company
你说我生完
replace me
这个孩子之后
with someone else
是不公司
after I have my baby?
没我位置了呀
No way.
不会
Impossible.
怎么可能
After giving birth,
你这生完孩子了
you'll only take a three to five-month
产假也就是
maternity leave, right?
三到五个月 是吧
There's no way they'll replace you.
怎么可能没有你的位置
You're the Content Director.
你是内容总监
But now there's a better fit
公司现在有比我
for Content Director than me.
更合适的内容总监了
She is younger,
年轻
and energetic,
有活力
with a fresh perspective.
思维也很活跃
All her focus
所有精力
is on work.
都能放在工作上
Whenever I see
我看着她做的
her performance,
这些业绩吧
I can't help but wonder
我就在想
if we're not as capable as she is,
我们是不是真的落伍了
and no longer needed?
没啥用了
I get what you're saying,
你说的这话 我能理解
but I don't agree.
但我不认同啊
They may be youthful,
年轻人固然是年轻
full of vigor and drive,
有活力 有干劲
yet they tend to make mistakes,
但是他们容易犯错啊
and take risks,
容易冒进
unlike us in middle age,
不像我们中年人
who are experienced,
有工作经验
reliable,
做事稳妥
and trusted by our bosses.
值得老板信任
The company certainly
那一个公司
needs to grow,
它固然是要发展
but stability is more crucial.
但是稳定才更重要
Moreover, there are
再说了 你看看
hardly any young executives
哪个公司的高管
in companies.
是年轻人
You're right.
有道理哈
So, now,
所以现在
just focus
你就踏踏实实
on nurturing pregnancy
安心地养胎
to ensure the smooth delivery
顺顺利利地
of our baby.
把孩子生下来
This is of
这件事
utmost importance
对于你
to you,
对于我们
to us,
对于我们这个家
and to our whole family.
那才是最重要的
But if they make a mistake,
那你说他们要是犯错了
should I point it out?
我是说呢 还是不说呢
Of course.
当然要说
You must.
该说就得说
You're still working,
你还干着这份工作呢
still getting paid, right?
拿这份钱呢 是吧
It's your responsibility.
这是你的责任
I must be responsible.
对得起良心得
Right.
对
This month, new member sign-ups
本月注册新会员
exceeded 300,000,
三十万加
New user activity
新用户活跃度
increased by 32%.
增长百分之三十二
The retention, conversion and ROI,
留存率 转化率 投产比
all get improved significantly.
均显著提升
We've surpassed Blue Ocean
已经超越蓝海
to become the company with the most
成为本地注册用户
registered users locally.
最多的公司
Though our market share is
虽然我们的市场份额
not as high as that of Blue Ocean,
还没有蓝海高
our shareholders
但是我们的股东啊
are quite satisfied
对我们近期的表现
with our recent performance.
还是很满意的
Mr. Zhang,
张总
with the traffic up,
咱们流量上来了
our marketing department's job
我们市场部的
got easier.
工作都好做了
In mere this month,
这个月
we saw
光是招商
a 30% increase in ad sales.
就提升了百分之三十
At this pace,
我觉得照这样发展下去
we might become
咱们成为市场第一
the market leader.
也不是没有可能的
Good.
好
If anyone else has any comments,
谁还有什么意见
any ideas,
有什么想法
now's the time to share.
现在就提
I'd like to mention
我还是想说一下
risk mitigation.
规避风险的事情
Network regulation
现在的网络监管
is tightening.
越来越完善
I've heard a few companies have
我听说已经有几家公司
already received fines.
接到罚单了
Rachel,
瑞秋啊
have you hired
让你招审核专员
the compliance officers?
你招了吗
I have.
招了
This is serious.
这是大事
I immediately posted
我第一时间就在网上
the job ads online.
发布了招聘启事
I noticed Miss Huang also got fined
我注意到黄总监在蓝海
when promoting this combination strategy
推这套组合拳的时候
in Blue Ocean.
也收到过罚单
I'm taking it seriously.
我很重视的
So, we must strengthen regulation.
所以呀 要加强监管哪
Meng'an,
梦安哪
the project
你说项目
is underway.
既然已经上马了
It's like a battle.
那就跟打仗一样
I said to charge ahead,
我说往前冲
so, let's not talk about pulling back.
你就别说往后退了
Otherwise, how can we win?
这仗还怎么打
Here's a thought: how about
你这样吧
you go help Mr. Zhou with debt collection?
你协助小周要账去吧
We have many outstanding receivables.
外面账欠得太多了
It hurts company operations.
也影响公司的运营
I'll personally handle
黄副总监这边呢
Miss Huang's issues.
我亲自来抓
Great.
那太好了
Mr. Zhang,
张总
since it's so important,
这么重要的事
I'll accompany Ms. Xu
那我跟许总监
to collect the debt.
一起去要账吧
She's a content creator.
她一搞内容的
It would be embarrassing for her
你 你让她去要账
to collect debts.
她拉不下那脸嘛
Besides, she is pregnant.
她就负责挺着肚子
She can just sit there,
往那儿一坐
and leave the negotiation to me.
我去跟他们谈
Maybe it'll work.
没准还有戏
Alright.
那行
Take care of Meng'an.
你照顾好梦安啊
Thank you, Rachel.
谢谢瑞秋
Thank you, Ms. Xu.
谢谢许总监
Maybe
要不
we can give Mr. Lin a call.
再给林总打个电话
Maybe tomorrow.
明天再打
We're done for today.
今天工作完成了
Let's
一会儿啊
head home soon.
咱们就各回各家
Doesn't that seem a bit off?
这不太好吧
Didn't you understand
张总的意思
Mr. Zhang's hint?
你没明白呀
He didn't mean for you to collect debts,
他是让你出来要账的吗
but rather wanted us to step out
咱俩就出来溜达溜达
refrain from interfering
不要干涉人家的
with their traffic plans.
流量大计
Our task is now complete.
就算完成任务
Later,
我等一下
I'll make a post
我还得
on WeChat Moments
发个朋友圈
and mention Huang Sisi.
我得艾特黄思思
Let her know
让她看看
how different
同样是工作
our work is.
差别就是这么大
You wanna have banquet on company's funds?
你不会打算公款吃喝吧
Mr. Zhang asked us
他不是让咱们
to collect debts.
出来要账吗
This meal will be considered a business expense,
这都是商务支出成本
and I'll ask Mr. Zhou to foot the bill.
我得让小周总掏钱呀
Don't bother,
算了啊
I'll take care of the bill.
还是我来吧
I don't want them
我现在这个样子
to think I'm exploiting
不能让他们觉得
the company
因为怀孕
because of my pregnancy.
就各种占公司便宜
They've already taken a dislike to me.
现在都看我不顺眼呢
How have you transformed,
我发现你这人怎么
since becoming pregnant,
一怀孕
from a tigress into a paper tiger?
母老虎就变纸老虎了
You don't know me well enough.
那是你对我不够了解
True,
确实
you're highly deceptive.
你这人欺骗性很强的
You seem to fear nothing,
看起来人五人六的
but that's all acting.
其实就是一个装
Soft inside, huh?
内心很   吧
You know how psychology
你知道这在心理学上
defines this?
怎么定义吗
Speak plainly.
你说简单点
Because
是因为
it is fear and anxiety
害怕和焦虑
that push you forward.
才迫使你往前走的
That's
这个出发点
not correct.
其实很不健康的
That stings.
扎心了啊
But this is the case
现在百分之九十的人
for 90% of the people nowadays.
都这样
You're not the only one.
你不是特别的那一个
What can I do?
那你说怎么办呢
I'm pregnant.
我现在怀孕
It's noticeable.
也显怀了
They all know that.
一看就知道我是个孕妇
Whenever I become emotional
我但凡有点情绪
and express a different opinion,
有点不同意见
they attribute it
他们就觉得
to high levels of pregnancy hormones.
我是孕激素过高
I'm pregnant,
我是怀孕
not stupid.
不是傻
Mr. Zhang even thinks
老张现在觉得
I am losing my mind.
我这儿有问题
That hurts. You know that?
这很伤人 你知道吗
You're fine.
你哪儿有问题
He won't fire you.
他也不会开了你
So just take it easy.
所以你就继续躺平吧
Is this the time to lie down?
这是躺平的时候吗
Clearly,
很明显呀
Mr. Zhang is
老张现在存着是
taking a gamble.
侥幸心理
Would you dare to let him gamble?
你敢让他赌吗
If he wins,
他赌赢了
I'm out.
我出局了
If he loses,
他赌输了
the company is doomed.
全公司都不在了
This isn't the time to take it easy.
这不是躺平的时候啊
So, what do you want to do?
那你想怎么办呀
It's not up to me.
我说了也不算哪
Then let him gamble.
那就让他找南墙吧
He won't turn back
不撞个头破血流
unless he loses everything.
他是不会回头的
It's not up to you anyway.
反正你说了也不算哪
Since
我发现
Little Watermelon was born,
这小西瓜生出来之后啊
you've been walking more steadily.
走路越来越有劲
I believe you'll
你是不是等
be able to run again
梦安生完了
once Meng'an gives birth.
你就能健步如飞了
See how well you walk!
你看 多有劲啊
Sit down and rest.
坐下 坐下 歇会儿
Sit down.
来 坐坐坐
Let me wipe the sweat
快擦擦汗
off your forehead.
这一脑门子汗呢
Almost finished.
等着 等着啊
It's all sweaty.
出这么些汗
Would you
那个
like a sip of water?
来 喝口水
Oh my, again I forgot to refill the bottle.
我又忘加水了
I... I won't
我 我下回
make the mistake again.
我下回我肯定不会忘
Blame on you.
谁让你啊
You always spoil me,
老让我做仙女
and never let me do any chores.
不让我做事
It's your fault.
都怪你
I think Xin and Haowen
我觉得心心和浩文
argued again.
肯定又吵架了
That's why she came back suddenly.
要不怎么突然回来了
Right?
是吧
Xin is definitely
心心
being capricious again.
肯定又任性了
Do you think so?
你说我说得对不对
Am I right?
对不对
But I think,
但我觉得吧
now that Xin has had a second child,
心心 生了二胎了
Haowen should
怎么着这个浩文
give her some slack.
你也应该让着她
Right?
是吧
If he's sensible,
你要懂事的话
how could he possibly argue with Xin?
怎么能跟她吵呢
He should be soothing her instead.
这哄还来不及呢
Am I wrong?
我说得不对啊
They've been arguing
好像最近
quite often recently.
吵得有点 勤
I'm concerned that
老吵嘛
their feelings of love fade
我就怕把这
due to the frequent fights.
感情给吵没了
Minor spats are no big deal,
小事没事
but this time it feels like
但我觉得这次好像有点
something's off.
不太对劲
What's your opinion?
你觉着呢
You... You got me confused.
不 你 你到底是
Do you agree or not?
对还是不对
Am I right?
我说得是不是对
Right.
对
Listen,
我跟你说
I think our whole family
我觉得现在咱们全家呀
should cater
那所有的人
to Xin's needs.
都得顺着心心的意
It's hard for a woman to give birth
那女人生孩子坐月子
and recover.
不容易啊
She needs to stay calm.
她就得气顺
You know,
我跟你说
if she stays calm,
气顺了之后
she won't have lingering issues.
她就不容易落病根
Right?
是不是
Right.
是
It makes sense, right?
有道理哈
Yes.
有
Well then,
那
you should talk to
那你是不是找个时间
Haowen about this matter.
跟浩文聊聊
I...
话
can't
说
speak clearly.
不清楚
You're overacting.
你有点演
Gotcha!
逗你玩
You old rascal,
你个臭老头你
you scared me!
你又吓我
Stop teasing me.
你老逗我
I'm scared to death.
吓死我了
Such an actor!
老演
Talk to Haowen about this when you are free.
有空你就找浩文聊聊嘛
Talk.
聊
Someone is fishing over there!
你看那边 钓鱼呢
Let's go and have a look.
咱 走走走 去看看
Looks like a big one.
好像钓上来
Let's go.
走走走 走
Sorry, I didn't support you properly,
我 扶得不对
using the wrong force.
劲使得不对
Careful.
慢点啊
Looks like they've caught a big one.
好像钓上来了个大的
Look.
你看
Xin,
心
I'm here to pick you up.
我来接你
I knew it.
我就知道
I knew you couldn't leave me.
我就知道你舍不得我
Let's go home.
回家
Pack your things.
收拾东西
Okay.
好
Then divorce.
离婚
Haowen!
浩文
Xin, you're awake.
心心 你醒了
Is Haowen here?
浩文来了
I... I made some cubilose soup for you.
我 我给你做了碗燕窝
I'll put it here.
先放在这儿
Remember to eat it.
一会儿记得喝
Mom,
妈
take care.
您慢点啊
Okay.
好嘞
Call me if you need anything.
随时有事给我打电话
Got it.
知道了
Have you got everything?
东西都拿齐了
Yes.
拿齐了
Do you have the house keys with you?
家钥匙都带了啊
Yes, I put them in this handbag.
家钥匙在这小包里
Mom, don't worry,
妈 您放心啊
this time I'll teach her
我这次非把她病
a lesson.
给治了不可
Don't be too harsh.
你可别做得这么绝呀
After all, Xin
好歹人家心心
did give you two kids.
给你生了俩孩子呢
If you feel embarrassed,
你要是抹不开面
I can
要不
visit your mother-in-law.
我去你岳母家去一趟
No need, mom.
不用 妈
Your son's smart enough
您儿子什么智商
to handle this.
这事我还摆不平
Don't worry.
放心
Alright.
好了
Call me when you get home.
到家给我打电话
Okay.
好
Be kinder to Xin.
好好过日子啊
I will.
放心
Don't quarrel with her.
别吵架
Alright.
好好好
Pluck those leaves.
把那叶择了啊
There you go.
对 对对
He hasn't fully recovered yet.
不太使得上劲
Leave it to me.
要不你别干了
I'll do it.
我来 我来 我来
Ma'am,
大姨
let him do it.
你 你得让他干
Go on, do it.
来来来 摘
Look, sir,
我跟你说 老爷子
look at me.
看见没
Pluck the leaf
这叶子 用劲把它
with force.
摘下来
He lacks strength.
他使不上劲
That's why I want him to do it by himself.
所以就让他锻炼呀
Life lies in movement.
生活运动很重要
And if
而且你看
he can pluck it,
他要是能摘下来
he will be more confident.
就增强他的信心
Sir,
老爷子
use your hands
你就得用 用手啊
to pluck the vegetables.
就 使劲摘这个菜
Right, use your hands.
对 你就得用手
Pluck it.
摘
Give it a try.
那试试 来
There you go.
来 试一试 试一试
Come on.
试一试
You can do this.
加油
See, he's smiling!
对 你看笑了吧
Gradually,
慢慢啊
he will be more confident.
他就有自信心了
Good, good.
行行行
Let me tell you
我再跟你说一说
how to manage his diet.
他这个饮食怎么调理
Just a moment,
你 你等会儿
I need to write it down.
我 我得记一下
You can take notes.
你记一下啊
His
你看
blood sugar
老爷子现在这个血糖
is slightly elevated, right?
不是有点偏高吗
He needs more than medication.
光用药也不行啊
Dietary regulation
怎么办
is essential.
必须要饮食调理
Cut down
米
on rice
面
and wheaten food,
少吃
as well as his intake of
但是有几样菜呢
some veggies, namely,
也要特别注意
pumpkin,
南瓜
pickled lotus root,
莲菜
and potatoes.
土豆
Pickled lotus root?
什么叫莲菜啊
It's made of lotus root.
莲菜就是莲藕嘛
Right.
对
Don't regard them merely as veggies.
这三个呢 它不是菜
Keep in mind
你记住
that they're staples,
它也是主食
and their consumption can lead to
吃了以后呢
a rapid increase in blood sugar levels.
升糖特别快
What should
老爷子这种情况
I do then?
怎么办呢
He can't go hungry.
也不能饿肚子吧
He needs to consume more whole grains.
就多吃一点粗粮
Is Little Watermelon crying?
小西瓜是不是哭了
Yes.
哭了
Did you hear that?
你听见了吗
Neither did I.
我也没有
Little Watermelon's crying?
小西瓜哭了啊
No.
没有啊
She just woke up,
刚睡了一觉 醒了
but didn't cry.
没哭 真的
I heard her cry.
我听见她哭了
No,
没有
she's fine.
好着的呢
Mommy's here.
妈妈来了
Mommy's here to see you.
妈妈来看你了
Pumpkin, lotus root, potatoes.
南瓜 莲藕 土豆
No.
不是
Whole grains,
粗粮
buckwheat.
荞麦
He can consume
像这个荞麦
more buckwheat.
就可以多吃
Plucking vegetables?
择菜呢
Meng'an is back.
梦安来了
Welcome back, An.
安安回来了
What's for dinner?
晚上吃什么呀
Celery dumplings.
芹菜馅饺子
Where's Xin?
心心呢
Just returned to her room.
刚回房间了
Be careful.
慢点啊
He's happy as soon as An returns.
安安回来他就亲
Yeah.
就是 就是
Let them chat.
让他俩唠去吧
Go on.
继续
The buckwheat...
你比如说荞麦
What's wrong?
怎么了
Xin,
心心
not right.
不对
Haowen
浩文
didn't pick her up.
没来接
Both
俩人
aren't right.
都不对
Check with Xin.
问问你妹妹
Okay.
好
You're back.
回来啦
What's up?
干吗呢
I've been sitting all day.
我这上班坐了一天
Let's take a walk.
陪姐出去走会儿啊
I'll look after the baby,
孩子有我呢
don't worry.
放心吧
You need a break.
去吧
Lanxiang will
叫小西瓜
take care of her.
让兰香姐看着
Don't worry.
不管她了
Let's go.
走
Come with me.
跟姐走
I feel as if I've returned to my childhood
感觉又回到了小时候
back when you would hold my hand
你也这么拉着我的手
and walk with me along the riverbank.
走在江边
What's wrong?
怎么啦
Am I too old
嫌我老啦
to walk fast now?
带不动你了
Of course not.
带得动
I want to be by your side forever.
我要黏你一辈子
Sounds great, let's take a rest.
来 跟姐黏一会儿
Xin,
心心啊
I've noticed you
我觉得你最近
seem a bit down lately.
是不是有点不太开心啊
What's bothering you?
愿意跟姐说说吗
Is everything ok?
是有什么事吗
I think Haowen has changed.
我觉得老贾有问题
Haowen?
老贾
Why do you say that?
又出什么问题了
He took
他把
all my luggage to our parents' house.
我的行李都拿回爸妈家
When did this happen?
什么时候的事啊
Just a few days ago.
就前两天
If it had been in the past,
要放以前
he would certainly come
他肯定会拿着
with plenty of gifts
大包小包的礼物来哄我
to cajole me into returning home.
把我哄回家
But this time, he simply set the gifts down
但他这次放下东西
and left.
就走了
I know he loves
他这么喜欢小孩的
kids, however,
一个人
this time, he barely spoke to Xiongxiong,
跟熊熊都没说上几句话
and didn't
小西瓜
even glance at Little Watermelon.
他连看都没看一眼
Something's off.
不对劲
Maybe you're overthinking.
是不是你想多了呀
Everyone sees how
那老贾对你什么样
Haowen treats you.
全家人都看在眼里
We wouldn't lie to you.
我们肯定不会骗你啊
Honestly,
说实话啊
I think you
我觉得这回
also went overboard this time.
你带着两个孩子
You came back with the two kids,
回娘家住
leaving Haowen to work alone
确实是有点不合适了
in a different city.
那你想想
He must be very upset
那老贾一个人
and lonely
在外边干事业
coming back
回到家
to
房子里头空空荡荡
an empty house.
冷冷清清的
It must have been tough for him.
他不难过呀
Maybe
没准
he's angry too,
他也有气呢
playing hard to get.
保不齐跟你斗气呢
Isn't that part of your relationship?
这不是你们夫妻情趣吗
But it's different this time.
这次不一样
Sometimes,
其实有时候
I'm frustrated with myself.
我也挺烦现在的自己的
I don't know what's wrong with me.
也不知道我到底怎么了
I feel like I'm a grumpy woman,
感觉自己像个怨妇一样
interested in
有时候对什么
nothing,
都提不起兴趣来
and dissatisfied
有时候又看什么
with anything.
看什么都不满意
I used to be
你说我以前
so confident,
多自信
and optimistic.
多乐观呀
But look at me now.
现在呢
I don't know why.
我也不知道怎么了
The moment
明明心里想的是一回事
I start to speak,
但是我一张嘴
my thoughts turn into
一张嘴就变成
something completely different.
另外一回事了
How did it come to this?
怎么会变成这个样子呀
It's so negative,
就是特别消极
just negativity.
就是消极
Xin,
心心啊
I have a suggestion:
姐有个建议啊
don't overthink it.
你也别多想
I feel that
主要是
you are in
姐觉得你现在的状态吧
a poor state of mind.
确实有点不太对
Would you like
你愿不愿意
to see
跟姐去看个
a therapist?
心理医生
I'm not saying you're sick.
姐不是说你有病
I can talk with you
姐也可以陪着你聊天
for as long as you need,
陪你多久都可以
but I think
但是我觉得
you need
你现在的状态
a professional
需要一个专业的人士
to help determine
来帮你判定一下
whether you're
你心理到底
okay or if something
是正常还是
is wrong.
有什么问题
Will you come with me?
你愿意吗
That's my girl.
乖
Let me give you a hug.
让姐抱抱
It's okay.
没事的
I'm here.
有姐啊
Everything will be fine.
一切都会好的
After childbirth, women
女人啊 生了孩子以后
experience changes.
会有一些变化
When a new baby
比如说家庭成员
joins the family,
多了一个宝宝
you start having all sorts
然后你就会产生
of thoughts.
很多的想法
In such case...
这样的一个状况开始呢
I took Xin
我带心心
to see a therapist.
去看心理医生了
The doctor said
大夫说
she does have some issues.
她确实有一点问题
Maybe she wasn't
可能是她从一开始
ready mentally
在心理上就没有做好
for a second child,
要怀二胎的准备
but due to family expectations,
但是因为身边人的期待
she still chose to have the child.
她还是选择了生产
Those conflicting feelings
但这两种情绪
are battling
在她心里
inside her,
不断地对抗着
making her
以至于
doubt everyone
她对身边的人
around her,
包括她自己
even herself.
都产生了怀疑
On top of that,
再加上
second-time moms don't get as much
大家对二胎孕产妇的
attention
关注度
as first-time moms,
没有初产妈妈高
which led to a significant
这也让她在心理上
psychological disparity for her.
有了极大的落差
I feel that since I had my second child,
我觉得我生完二胎之后
my family
家人
has distanced themselves from me.
他们都疏远我了
It seems
他们好像
they are unwilling to talk to me.
都不愿意跟我说话
At home,
在家里的时候
my husband,
我老公
my mother-in-law,
我婆婆
my dad, my mom,
我爸 我妈
and even the nanny ignored me.
就连月嫂都是
It's strange.
我觉得特别奇怪
At home,
在家里的时候
they're all busy,
他们都 都各忙各的
too busy.
都好像很忙的样子
But I,
可是我
I'm useless.
我什么都帮不上忙
Sometimes,
他们有时候
they walked past me
从我身边走过去
as if I don't exist.
就好像看不见我一样
It was my fault.
是我疏忽了
I failed to offer her
没有在这段时间里面
more mental support and comfort
给她更多的心理疏导
during that time,
和安抚
and it made her sad.
让她难过了
She can get through this.
你妹妹能挺过去
Families need to face tough times together.
家不能散了
I went on an outing a couple of days ago,
我前两天去郊游了
basking in the sunshine,
享受阳光啊
and embracing
大自然带给你的
nature.
那些东西
Quite relaxing.
特别治愈
During that time,
然后在这个过程当中呢
my sister stayed with me,
我姐也一直陪着我
comforting me.
在开导我
Maybe opening up makes it
可能把心打开了之后
easier to accept others.
也更容易包容别人
That's great.
真好 真棒
Mom, I'm back!
妈 我回来了
Ying!
英子姐
Haowen!
浩文
How is it? Did it pass?
怎么样 通过了吗
Passed or not?
通过没通过啊
Check yourself.
自己看啊
Passed!
通过啦
The partners' reaction
合作方对
to investing in Blue Ocean was positive.
投资蓝海的反响都不错
Congratulations, Mr. Yu.
恭喜你啊 于总
Thanks, thanks, thanks.
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
I must thank you.
这 这我得感谢你
It's only because of your help
完全是因为你的帮助
that I passed.
才能通过
It wasn't me.
真不是我
It was Yaohui and Mr. Zhou's
是耀辉和周总
stellar reputation.
这块金字招牌
No,
哪儿啊
before you came on board,
在你介入这个项目之前
I was chasing Yaohui
我已经盯耀辉
for half a year.
盯了半年了
Without your help,
如果没有你的帮助啊
my proposal
我那计划书
wouldn't have reached Mr. Zhou's desk.
都上不了周总的办公桌
Maybe it's because
那可能是我对你
I understand you
和蓝海的认识
and Blue Ocean better.
比较深入吧
But I must warn you
但是我要把这个风险
of the risks in advance.
提前告诉你啊
Hold on,
等等
let's talk about this some other time, okay?
咱们改天说好不好
What's wrong?
怎么了
I have
我现在啊
to rush back to the office
就要赶回到公司去
for a transition meeting.
有一个转型的会议
It's crucial.
非常的重要
I must go now.
我现在就得走
Can we reschedule?
咱们再约时间 好吗
Maybe to another time.
再约时间
We're just...
我们就是
Sorry!
同学 对不起
You two, hurry up!
你 你俩快点
It serves you right, Zhu Kexin!
撞得好 朱可欣
You deserve it.
活该
He Lu, don't say that.
何璐 你别说
She treated you like that,
她都这么对你了
yet you're still defending her?
你还帮她说话
She hurt me,
她是坑我了
but I can't
但我也不能
kick her when she's down.
盼望着她被撞啊
You claimed your mom is a saint.
你还说你妈是个圣母呢
I think
我看啊
you're excessively kind, too.
你也是个小圣母
I certainly am not.
我哪有
Her notebook.
笔记本
Return it to her.
还给人家吧
Honey.
老公
Welcome back.
回来了
Do you think I'm sincere
你看我这个诚意
enough?
可以吗
Absolutely.
太可以了
We've agreed before
不是说好了
you'd help save my face.
扶我下台阶吗
Yunjie,
云阶
your mom bought you
你看你妈给你带什么
lots of tasty treats.
好吃的回来了
Come and take a look.
来 来 来 看
Why did you buy them?
你什么意思啊
It may not
虽然它看起来
seem healthy,
没那么健康
but
但是
sometimes,
我们有时候
we need it
那些负面情绪
to improve our moods,
就是要靠它来抚平的
right?
对吧
Mommy.
妈妈
I thought you'd hug fried chicken.
我还以为你要抱炸鸡呢
See?
我就说
No grudges between mother and daughter.
母女哪有隔夜仇啊
Right?
是吧
Come on,
快快 抓紧时间
let's savor the fried chicken
趁你大姑不在家
while your aunt is away!
我们炸鸡大餐
Zhu Kexin's father
朱可欣爸爸
not only neglects them
不但不管她们
but even asks them for money.
还和她们要钱呢
How could
没想到啊
her father treat her
朱可欣他们家
like this?
是这么个情况呀
Exactly, so I can't
是呀 所以我觉得
hold a grudge against her
我也不能再揪着
anymore,
她不放了
and He Lu won't call her
何璐也不会
by nicknames any longer.
再给她起外号了
By comparison,
相比他们家
I feel
我觉得咱们家
we're truly blessed.
真的幸福太太 太多了
But she gets good grades
那他们家都这样了
even with all this.
还能考那么好呢
Why do you always
你怎么又来啊
bring up my scores?
又扯到学习上面
And now you'll
下句是不得
link it to me, right?
联想到我身上了
You little genius,
你个小机灵鬼
can't you channel this genius...
能不能把这个机灵劲
into...
放
Into my studies?
都用到学习上面去
I know you well.
你看我多了解你
Dad,
爸
help me!
救救我
Dad.
又怎么了
Mom starts lecturing again.
妈又开始了
Again?
又开
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
you kids don't understand.
你小孩子 你不知道
Don't dismiss
有时候你不要
what adults say.
嫌弃大人说话啊
There's a song that goes,
有首歌不是唱挺好吗
"Listen to mom's words."
听妈妈的话
The baby's kicking, honey.
胎动了 老公
Kicking?
胎动
Where?
在哪儿啊
In my belly.
肚子里
When did it start?
什么时候开始的
Just now.
刚开始
It's the first time.
这应该还是第一回呢
Why isn't it kicking?
他怎么也不动啊
Little Grape, kick for me.
小葡萄 你动一动呗
I'm your sister,
我是你姐姐
Come on, give it a kick.
你听我的 动一动
Be good, kick.
听话 动一动
It really works!
动了
Right.
对
Here.
这儿
It's kicking!
动了 动了
Kicking!
动了
Here, here!
就就就 就这儿
Feel it, feel it.
你摸你摸 你看
Put your hand here.
放你爸这儿
Here.
就 就这儿
Right?
是不是
It's really kicking!
真动了 真动了
It's turning sideways.
翻身呢
No,
什么呀
it's following
这是我刚跟他说完
my words.
他听我的话呢
Yes... You're right.
听你的 听你的
So, make sure it behaves,
那你以后得管着他点
like your mom cares for Xin,
就像你妈管你小姨一样
Got it?
知道吧
Okay!
好
I can now give orders as well!
我也有能管的人喽
Little Grape,
小葡萄
focus all your attention
以后把你的精神头
on your studies!
全给我用学习上
You hear me?
听到了吗
Really?
至于吗
Yes, really.
至于 特别至于
I'm so happy!
好开心啊
Little Grape!
小葡萄
Yu Hai,
于海
you booked the whole place again?
你不会又包场了吧
I really don't like
我特别不喜欢
your random sense
你这种莫名其妙的
of ceremony.
仪式感
What a nice cake.
蛋糕不错
The kids will love it.
孩子们一定会喜欢的
I'll take it back for them.
一会儿我带回去
A token from their dad.
爸爸的一片心意嘛
Thanks.
谢谢了啊
No need.
谢什么呀
I've put the gifts
那个给孩子们的礼物啊
for the kids
我已经放到
into your car's trunk.
你车的后备箱里了
You've become thoughtful,
长心了呀
even remembering to buy gifts
还知道给孩子们
for the kids.
买礼物了
I know. I know.
我知道 我知道
I know
我知道
I've been
我以前呢
terrible before.
实在是做得不好
Last year,
你像去年
I wasn't able to get back
我都没能赶回来
for their birthdays.
给孩子过生日
What do you mean by that?
你什么意思呀
Hinting that I'm not with the kids
你这影射我今年
for their birthday this year?
不能陪孩子过生日呗
No,
没有
no, no, no!
没有 没有 没有
I wouldn't dare.
打死我都不敢
That's not what I meant.
我不是这个意思
Don't worry,
放心
I've talked with them
我跟她们商量好了
about making up for it.
我会补过的
Then,
那
can I join in too?
到时候能不能也叫上我
I'd love to be part of it.
我也凑凑热闹
No problem.
没问题啊
I'll invite you,
我到时候叫上你
but stop
不过你不要
with these gestures.
再搞这种套路了
The kids have their own likes.
孩子们有自己的喜好
Okay.
好的
But I think,
但是我觉得啊
actually,
其实这个
for the birthdays,
孩子们过生日吧
I think,
我觉得
who deserves
我觉得最应该感激的人
the most gratitude.
其实是你
Take a look, please.
你看 你看 你看 不是
I'm just
我 我就是
a regular guy, right?
这么一个俗人 是吧
Will you ever stop?
有完没完啊你
Yes, yes.
是是是
Look at you,
尤其是你啊
you
你说
gave me two daughters.
你一下给我生两个女儿
Their birthday
她们俩出生那天
is your suffering day.
那就是你的受难日
You suffered.
你太辛苦了
Take it.
来
Thanks.
谢了啊
At least you didn't put it in the cake.
还好没有放蛋糕里
That'd be too tacky.
那就太俗了
Even I couldn't stand that.
那这我都受不了
I've always known
其实我一直都知道
you're better than me.
你比我要强
I've reflected a lot lately.
我这段时间反思了
Deep down,
好多东西
I realized
我发现其实在我自己
I was afraid
内心的最深处啊
you would surpass me.
我是怕你比我强
After you had the kids,
你生完孩子之后我就想
I wanted you to stay home,
让你在家照顾孩子
to trap you there.
这样把你困在那儿
I didn't want you to work,
我不让你出来工作
otherwise, I would lose
要不然我在家里
my place at home.
我就没地位了
It's wrong.
对不对
I was so selfish.
我太自私了
I owe you an apology.
所以我得向你道歉
Apology accepted.
接受你的道歉
But our separation has
不过我们现在这样分开
been good for us.
各自都发展得挺好
Right?
不是吗
No, no, no.
不不不
You can't say that.
这 这话咱不能这么说
If I'm no longer selfish,
如果说我不再自私了
I mean,
我是说如果啊
if I've changed,
如果说我改了
then we...
那咱们俩
If you're really bored,
如果你实在闲得慌
look over these files.
你看一下资料吧
What's wrong with your eyes?
你眼睛怎么了
I'm getting farsighted.
我 我开始老花了
But your eyesight was
你原来眼睛不是
always good.
挺好的吗
Yeah,
是
the doctor said
医生说啊
people with good eyesight in their youth
年轻的时候眼睛越好
are more prone to presbyopia
到这个岁数
as they age.
眼睛越容易花
In high school,
你想我高中的时候
I even passed the pilot exam
我还考过飞行员呢
with 20/20 vision.
我这二点零
Haowen!
浩文
Hotpot noodles.
火锅面
Looks familiar, right?
火锅面你看着熟悉吧
Before,
之前
we ate it almost every day
我们在服装市场的时候
at the clothing market,
几乎天天都吃的
remember?
你记得吗
Stop reminiscing.
不要忆苦思甜了
Haowen,
浩文
I was wrong.
我错了
Let's reconcile.
我们和好吧
I won't act up anymore.
今后我不作了
Let's live a good life.
我们好好过日子
okay?
好不好
I'm talking to you, Haowen.
我跟你说话呢 浩文
Let's get a divorce.
我们离婚吧
Why?
为什么离婚啊
You tell me.
你说呢
Haowen, I was wrong.
浩文 我错了
I was wrong!
我错了
I really know my mistake!
我真的知道错了
I'll behave well from now on,
以后我都听你的
please.
好不好
I was too willful before.
之前是我太任性了
I didn't care
我一发起脾气来
about your feelings.
我就不顾你的感受
I took advantage
我仗着你对我好
of your kindness.
我就欺负你
That's all on me.
这些都是我不对
Forgive me, okay?
你原谅我好不好 浩文
I've started seeing a therapist.
我已经去看心理医生了
If I actively cooperate with treatment,
只要我积极配合治疗
I'll get better.
我都会好起来的
Haowen, Hao...
浩文 浩
Xu Mengxin,
许梦心
a harmonious family is essential.
家和万事兴
But you stir up trouble every day,
你每天闹得鸡犬不宁
making it impossible for me
我根本就没有办法
to focus on work.
认真工作
I have to handle both the family
我忙完了家里
and work.
忙工作
I barely had time
我一刻喘息的机会
to breathe.
都没有